Guide to the Fred Chappell Papers, 1944-2019 and undated RL.00213
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1955-1997 and undated
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1956-1997 and undated
    - 1989 (Box PM-2)
      - Cotton Boll, Vol. 4, No. 1, Winter: interview by William Walsh (Box PM-2)
    - 1990
      - Kentucky Poetry Review, Vol. 26, No. 2, Fall: Fred Chappell Issue (Box PM-2)
      - Poetry Review, Winter: Interview by S.A. Stirnemann (Box PM-2)
    - 1991
      - Manoa, Vol. 3, No. 1, Spring: For Whom Does the Poet Write? 25 Poets Respond to Fred Chappell (Box PM-2)
      - Caesura, No. 11, Spring: Interview by Anne Colwell (Box PM-2)
      - Pembroke Magazine, No. 23: NC Writers Honor Fred Chappell section (Box PM-2)
      - Editor's Choice III: Introduction (Box PM-2)
    - 1992
      - Chronicles: A Magazine of American Culture, Mar.: The Polymorph, by Gregory McNamee (review of Chappell's More Shapes Than One) (Box PM-2)
      - Omni, Vol. 14, No. 19, June: Science Superheroes (editorial) (Box PM-2)
      - Appalachian Journal, Vol. 19, No. 4, Summer: interview by Tersh Palmer (Box PM-2)
      - Ghent, Oct.: interview by Marion Blue and excerpt from Earthsleep (Box PM-2)
      - Mid-American Review, Vol. 13, No. 1: interview of Stuart Wright (Box PM-2)
    - 1993
      - Now and Then, Vol. 10, No. 1, Spring: Of Mr. Ward & Mrs. Dixon & Miss Belle & Chief (Box PM-2)
      - The Enterprise, May 5: Fred Chappell--Canton's Own Thomas Wolfe (interview/biography by Peggy Gosselin) (Box PM-2)
      - Die Young, No. 6, Summer: two poetry translations (Box PM-2)
      - Duke Magazine, Vol. 80, No. 1, Nov.-Dec.: Laboring in Literary Fields: Fred Chappell: the Bard of Canton, by Georgann Eubanks (Box PM-2)
      - Deathrealm, Issue 20, Winter: letter to the editor (Box PM-2)
      - Crisis, Dec.: Poems for the Home (Box PM-2)
      - Pembroke Magazine, 25: Tribute to Wilma Dykeman (Box PM-2)
    - 1994
      - La Quinzame, No. 649, June 16-30: interview by Andre Bleikasten (Box PM-2)
      - Weird Tales, No. 1, Summer: interview with Darrell Schweitzer (Box PM-2)
      - Georgetown Review, Vol. 3, No. 1, Fall: two poetry translations (Box PM-2)
      - Anglican Theological Review, Vol. 76, No. 1, Winter: four poetry translations (Box PM-2)
      - UNC-G Alumni News: Winter: You've Got to Continue to Persevere (interview by Christi Cook) (Box PM-2)
      - The Siren: two poetry translations (Charles d'Orleans) (Box PM-2)
      - The Formalist, Vol. 5, Issue 1: poetry translation (Box PM-2)
    - 1995
      - North Carolina Writers' Network: the Network News, Vol. 11, No. 4, July/Aug.: photograph of Chappell at Keep the Lights Burning for Literature (Box PM-2)
      - GW: Magazine for the Guilford County Woman, Vol. 2, No. 2, Oct./Nov.: announcement of reading to benefit Women's Resource Center of Greensboro (Box PM-2)
      - Challenger, No. 3, Fall/Winter: letter to editor (Box PM-2)
      - The Archive, Vol. 108, no. 1, Fall: interview by Leila Easa (Box PM-2)
      - Pembroke Magazine, No. 27: contributing editor (Box PM-2)
    - 1996
      - The Motley, 1995-1996: interview by Jason Aubuchon (Box PM-2)
      - Notre Dame Review, No. 2, Summer: interview by Kevin Corbett (Box PM-2)
      - Yale Journal of Law & the Humanities, Vol. 8, No. 1, Winter: Cardinal Newman and Jury Verdicts: Reason, Belief, and Certitude, article by Colin Moran, with pencilled annotations by Chappell (Box PM-2)
    - 1997
      - Challenger, No. 5, Winter: letter to editor (Box PM-2)
      - Word Art 1997, Feb.: poetry juror (Box PM-2)
    - N.d.
      - Duke Writing: The William Blackburn Legacy (Box PM-2)
    - 1971-1996 and undated
      - Publishers' catalogs (Box PM-2)
  - Clippings Subseries, ca. 1955-1997 and undated
    Clippings about Chappell and his work, tearsheets of his publications--mainly reviews--in newspapers and journals, etc. Clippings about the author are arranged chronologically at the beginning and works by him are arranged by genre at the end of the series.
    - Clippings, 19 folders (Box PC-1)
- Miscellaneous Series, ca. 1960-1997 and undated
  Various material about Chappell's personal and professional life, including: bibliographies; publicity material about or from organizations of which he is an officer or member; genealogical research; samples of fan mail; and audiovisual materials containing readings by and interviews with Chappell as well as materials sent to him by other writers. Organized in three subseries: Personal and Professional Papers, Audio Materials, and Video Materials. For clippings about Chappell's works, see Printed Materials Series, Clippings Subseries.
  - Personal and Professional Papers Subseries, 1960-1997 and undated
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1960-1988, 12 folders (Box MP-1)
    - 1989-1993, 10 folders (Box MP-2)
    - 1994-1997 and undated, 9 folders and plaque (Box MP-3)
    - Correspondence separated from audiovisual items, 1991-1997 and undated, 1 folder (Box MP-3)
  - Audio Materials Subseries, 1987-1997 and undated
    Audio cassettes of readings and other public appearances by Chappell, his writings as presented by other authors, and miscellaneous recordings of other authors. Arranged chronologically within three sub-subseries: Writings by Chappell, Miscellaneous, and Writings by Others. There are four copies of each item: the original, the master, the submaster, and the use copy. Only the use copy is available to researchers.
    - Writings by Chappell Sub-subseries (Use Copies)
      Audio cassettes of readings by Chappell. Arranged chronologically. See Audiovisual Subseries note for usage details.
      - 1987 Nov. 12: Reading in support of Blue Pitcher (Box AVU-1)
      - 1989 Jun. 11 - Jul. 23: Wedding Cake Stories, National Public Radio (Box AVU-1)
      - 1989 Oct. 22: Poets' Corner Vespers Service, Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine (Box AVU-1)
      - 1992 Dec. 20: Asinaria (Box AVU-1)
      - 1994 Apr. 21: Chappell reading three translated poems, produced by Miriam Graham, WDAV (Box AVU-1)
      - 1995: First Words: Earliest Writing from Favorite Contemporary Authors (incl. Chappell) (Box AVU-1)
        Original copy can by used.
      - 1997 Apr. 24: Fred Chappell: Farewell and David Mason: The Country I Remember, Soundings, National Humanities Center (Box AVU-1)
      - N.d.: Eastern Music Festival Triptych, narration by Fred Chappell, music by Robert Ward (Box AVU-1)
    - Miscellaneous Sub-subseries (Use Copies)
      Audio cassettes of interviews, conferences, and other events about Chappell. Arranged chronologically. See Audio Materials Subseries note for usage details.
      - 1990 Jul. 28: N.C. Writers Network Conference honoring Chappell (Box AVU-1)
      - 1991 Apr. 21: N.C. Poetry Society, 2 tapes (Box AVU-1)
    - Writings by Others Sub-subseries (Use Copies)
      Audio cassettes of writings by other authors. Arranged chronologically. See Audio Materials Subseries note for usage details.
      - 1993 Dec. 16: O'Callahan, Jay, Jeremy: A Christmas Story (Box AVU-1)
        Original copy; use copy will be made on request.
      - N.d.: Carden, Gary, Stories (Box AVU-1)
      - N.d.: Faulkner, William, selected readings (Box AVU-1)
      - N.d.: Garrett, George, reading from Fox and Succession (Box AVU-1)
      - N.d.: Garrett, George, interviewed for American Audio Prose Library (Box AVU-1)
      - N.d.: March, Steve, songs (Box AVU-1)
      - Original copies (Box AVO-1)
        Conditions Governing Access note
        Closed. Refer to Use Copies above for access.
      - Master copies (Box AVM-1)
      - Sub-master copies (Box AVSM-1)
  - Video Materials Subseries, 1988-1995
    Video cassettes of readings and other public appearances by Chappell, his writings as presented by other authors, and miscellaneous recordings of other authors. Arranged chronologically within two sub-subseries: Miscellaneous and Writings by Others. Use copies will be made on request; consult with Research Services.
    - Miscellaneous Sub-subseries (Original Copies)
      Video cassettes of interviews, conferences, and other events about Chappell. Arranged chronologically. Use copies made on request.
      - undated, ca. 1988: North Carolina English Teachers Association, presentation of Chappell with Sam Ragan/Louis Rubin award, VHS videocassette (Box AVO-1)
      - 1995 Nov. 9: NC Now Newsmaker interview with Chappell, VHS videocassette (Box AVO-1)
    - Writings by Others Sub-subseries (Use Copies)
      Video cassettes of writings by other authors. Arranged chronologically. See Video Materials Subseries note for usage details.
      - 1993 Oct. 28: Skellings, Edmund, Superpoems, VHS videocassette (Box AVO-1)
- Writings by Others Series, 1966-1997 and undated
  Arranged alphabetically by author. Contains manuscripts, typescripts, proofs, and printed material sent by other authors to Chappell. The writers include colleagues, current and former students, editors and writers sending the work of a third person(s), and fans. In general, writings sent as attachments to letters appear in the Correspondence Series, Incoming Correspondence Subseries; the writings that appear here are items sent separately, with only brief notes, or items such as complete drafts of books that were too large to be foldered as an attachment to correspondence.
  - Abbott, Anthony, S., 1991 (Box WO-1)
  - Ackerman, Diane, 1979 (Box WO-1)
  - Adamour, Beth, undated (Box WO-1)
  - Adams, Elizabeth Nelson, 1994 (Box WO-1)
  - Adcock, Betty, 1994 (Box WO-1)
  - Allen, Gay Wilson, 1991, 1994, 2 folders (Box WO-1)
  - Allen, Gilbert, 1991 (Box WO-1)
  - American Academy of Poets Contest, 1987 (Box WO-1)
  - Ammons, A.R. See Oversize Material (Box WO-1)
  - Anderson, Kent, 1992, 1994, 2 folders (Box WO-1)
  - Andrews, Claudia Emerson, 1997 (Box WO-1)
  - Appalachian Mountain Books, 1988 (Box WO-1)
  - Applewhite, James, 1960-1993, 3 folders (Box WO-1)
  - Asheville Poetry Review, 1996 (Box WO-1)
  - Associated Writing Programs Contest, 1985 (Box WO-1)
  - Athas, Daphne, 1991 (Box WO-1)
  - Austin, William M., 1994 (Box WO-1)
  - Baer, William, 1997 (Box WO-1)
  - Barkley, Brad 1995 (Box WO-1)
  - Barks, Coleman, 1984-1993, 4 folders (Box WO-1)
  - Barnes, Jim, 1985 (Box WO-1)
  - Barnhill, Anne, 1995 (Box WO-1)
  - Barr, Charlotte, 1993 (Box WO-1)
  - Barrax, Gerald, 1991 (Box WO-1)
  - Baskin, John, 1969 (Box WO-1)
  - Basney, Lionel, 1996 (Box WO-1)
  - Bayes, Ronald H., 1983, 1993, 2 folders (Box WO-1)
  - Beam, Jeffrey, 1992 (Box WO-1)
  - Beaufort, Bowman, 1969 (Box WO-1)
  - Benz, Maudy, 1997 (Box WO-2)
  - Bernardin, Libby, 1994 (Box WO-2)
  - Berry, Wendell, 1997 (Box WO-2)
  - Betts, Doris, 1996 (Box WO-2)
  - Blackburn, Alexander, 1994, 2 folders (Box WO-2)
  - Blackwell, Kate, 1987 (Box WO-2)
  - Brilliant, Alan, 1980 (Box WO-2)
  - Britt, Alan, 1996 (Box WO-2)
  - Brooker, Jewel Spears, 1993 (Box WO-2)
  - Brown, Linda Beatrice, 1996 (Box WO-2)
  - Bugeja, Michael, 1990 (Box WO-2)
  - Bulgin, Kathleen, 1983 (Box WO-2)
  - Byer, Kathryn Stripling, 1992, 1992, 2 folders (Box WO-2)
  - Calhoun, Robert M., 1985 (Box WO-2)
  - Campbell, Mary Belle, 1991 (Box WO-2)
  - Campbell, Ewing, 1985-1988, 1988, 2 folders (Box WO-2)
  - Card, Orson Scott, 1990 (Box WO-2)
  - Challender, Craig, 1986-1987 (Box WO-2)
  - Cherry, Kelly, 1975-1994 and undated, 14 folders (Box WO-2)
  - Childers, David, 1991, 1993, 2 folders (Box WO-2)
  - Cities and Roads, 1995-1996 (Box WO-2)
  - Clark, Jim, undated (Box WO-2)
  - Cleary, Michael, undated (Box WO-2)
  - Clem, Robert, 1985 (Box WO-3)
  - Clift, G.W., 1995, 1996, 2 folders (Box WO-3)
  - Cofer, Judith Ortiz, 1993 (Box WO-3)
  - Cohen, Marty, 1979 (Box WO-3)
  - Colander, Valerie, 1991-1997, 4 folders (Box WO-3)
  - Conner, Wilkie, 1995 (Box WO-3)
  - Coogan, Garth, 1991 (Box WO-3)
  - Coulter, Hope Norman, 1988 (Box WO-3)
  - Courtois, Wayne, 1986 (Box WO-3)
  - Creely, Robert, 1991 (Box WO-3)
  - Crivy, Joseph, undated (Box WO-3)
  - Crowe, Thomas Rain, 1993 (Box WO-3)
  - Dancy, Vera Branch, 1989 (Box WO-3)
  - Darnell, Donald, undated (Box WO-3)
  - Davis, William Virgil, 1992 (Box WO-3)
  - Davis-Gardner, Angela, 1996 (Box WO-3)
  - Dawson, Carl, 1995 (Box WO-3)
  - Dayton, Irene, 1990 (Box WO-3)
  - Deagon, Ann, 1996 (Box WO-3)
  - Depta, Victor M. 1995 (Box WO-3)
  - Diekcy, James, 1990 (Box WO-3)
  - Dillard, Anne, 1970, and undated, 2 folders (Box WO-3)
  - DiSanto, Grace, undated, 1975-1982, 4 folders (Box WO-3)
  - Dixon, Arthur, undated (Box WO-3)
  - Dixon, K. Reynolds, 1996 (Box WO-3)
  - Doar, Harriet, 1983 (Box WO-3)
  - Doyle, Lynn, undated (Box WO-3)
  - Driskell, Kathleen Mason, undated (Box WO-3)
  - Duncan, Julia Nunnally, 1994 (Box WO-4)
  - Duncan, David James, 1994 (Box WO-4)
  - Durban, Pam, 1993 (Box WO-4)
  - Dykeman, Wilma, 1996 (Box WO-4)
  - Eaton, Charles Edward, 1996 (Box WO-4)
  - Edens, Mark Edward, 1990, 1991, 2 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Edgerton, Clyde, 1991, 1995 (Box WO-4)
  - Ellis, James, undated (Box WO-4)
  - Epstein, Daniel Mark, 1995, 2 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Epstein, Joseph, undated (Box WO-4)
  - Esteban, Cooper, 1994 (Box WO-4)
  - Ferguson, Chris, 1986 (Box WO-4)
  - Ferguson, Oliver, 1965 (Box WO-4)
  - Ferrell, Anderson, 1996 (Box WO-4)
  - Field, Bob, undated (Box WO-4)
  - Fleming, Thomas, 1988 (Box WO-4)
  - Flynt, Candace, undated, 1984, 2 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Foriyes, Tina, 1989 (Box WO-4)
  - Fort, Charles, 1989-1995, 3 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Fortunato, Peter, 1995 (Box WO-4)
  - Fowlie, Wallace, 1987 (Box WO-4)
  - Frazier, Tony J., undated (Box WO-4)
  - Galvin, Brendan, 1988 (Box WO-4)
  - Garrett, George, 1981-1997 and undated, 15 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Gilgun, John, 1993 (Box WO-4)
  - Gingher, Marianne, 1996 (Box WO-4)
  - Gingher, Robert, 1993 and undated, 2 folders (Box WO-4)
  - Gioia, Dana, 1990 (Box WO-4)
  - Glass, Jesse, 1990-1991 (Box WO-5)
  - Goding, Cecile, 1992 (Box WO-5)
  - Grace, Eugene, 1986 (Box WO-5)
  - Green, Coppie, 1986 (Box WO-5)
  - Green, Lewis, 1970 (Box WO-5)
  - Gresset, Michel, undated (Box WO-5)
  - Grimsley, Jim, 1996 (Box WO-5)
  - Growth and Change, 1996 (Box WO-5)
  - Gurganus, Allan, 1996 (Box WO-5)
  - Gwynn, R.S., 1989, 1993, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Hall, James, 1991, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Hall, Sidney, Jr., 1993, 1997, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Hall, William Keith, 1995 (Box WO-5)
  - Hankla, Cathryn, 1991, 1997, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Harold, William, 1988 (Box WO-5)
  - Harmon, Willian, 1980, 1997 (Box WO-5)
  - Harris, Ken, undated (Box WO-5)
  - Hawkins, Tom, 1985 (Box WO-5)
  - Hester, M.L., 1995 (Box WO-5)
  - Hickman, Lynn, 1989 (Box WO-5)
  - Higgs, Robert, 1983 (Box WO-5)
  - Hilla, Donald P., Jr. 1996 (Box WO-5)
  - Hix, H.L., 1995, 1996, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Honeycutt, Irene Blair, 1992 (Box WO-5)
  - Hopes, David Brendan, 1996 (Box WO-5)
  - Howes, Barbara, 1985 (Box WO-5)
  - Huey, Tom, 1979, 1991 and undated, 3 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Hughes, Gladys Owings, 1990 (Box WO-5)
  - Hulbert, John, undated (Box WO-5)
  - Hummer, T.R., 1996 and undated, 2 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Humphries, Jefferson, 1989-1995, 4 folders (Box WO-5)
  - Jackson, Joel, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Jacobs, Lucky, 1993, 1995, 2 folders (Box WO-6)
  - James, Hunter, 1993 (Box WO-6)
  - Janus (Journal of Literature), 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Jarrell, Mary, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Johnson, Don, 1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Johnson, Larry, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Johnston-Hale, Ellen T., 1993 (Box WO-6)
  - Jolly, John, 1986 (Box WO-6)
  - Jones, Liz, 1997 (Box WO-6)
  - Junkins, Donald, 1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Katrovas, Richard, 1993 (Box WO-6)
  - Katz, Arlene, 1978 (Box WO-6)
  - Kaufman, Debra, 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Kaufman, Wallace, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Kelly, Mary Torre, 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Kelly, Pete, 1991 (Box WO-6)
  - Kennedy, X.J., 1993-1994, 1996, 2 folders (Box WO-6)
  - Kessel, John, 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Kirby-Smith, H.T., 1981 (Box WO-6)
  - Kuzma, Greg, 1995 (Box WO-6)
  - Kyles, Carolyne, 1991 (Box WO-6)
  - Lane, John Edwards, 1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Lebovitz, Richard, 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Lea, Sydney, 1980 (Box WO-6)
  - Lentricchia, Melissa, 1988 (Box WO-6)
  - Levinson, James Heller, 1989-1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Lilly Peter Fellowships, 1985 (Box WO-6)
  - Linney Romulus, 1996 (Box WO-6)
  - Locke, Duane, 1994 (Box WO-6)
  - Louis Adrian C., 1992 (Box WO-6)
  - Lucas, Marie Beaudry, 1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Luschei, Glenna, 1994 (Box WO-6)
  - Lynskey, Edward C., 1990 (Box WO-6)
  - Lyon, George Ella, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Maddela, Anthony Edward, 1996, 3 folders (Box WO-6)
  - Maiolo, Joseph, 1972 See also Oversize Material (Box WO-6)
  - Makuck, Peter, undated (Box WO-6)
  - Malouf, Melissa. See Melissa Lentricchia. (Box WO-6)
  - March, Stephen, 1995, 2 folders (Box WO-6)
  - Marginalia, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Marion, Jeff Daniel, 1993 and undated (Box WO-7)
  - Maron, Margaret, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Martin, Carl R. 1986, 1991 (Box WO-7)
  - Mason, David, 1995, 2 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Matamoros, Gustavo, 1989 (Box WO-7)
  - McCrumb, Sharon, 1984 (Box WO-7)
  - McCurdy, Harold G., 1995 (Box WO-7)
  - McDonald, Walter, 1980 (Box WO-7)
  - Mcdougall, Jo, 1990 (Box WO-7)
  - McFee, Michael, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - McFerren, Martha, 1992 (Box WO-7)
  - McKee, Glenn, 1990 (Box WO-7)
  - McKernan, John, 1995 (Box WO-7)
  - Meads, Kat, 1995 (Box WO-7)
  - Middleton, David, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Middleton, Ed, 1990, 1991, 2 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Milby, June, 1993, 2 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Miller, Heather Ross, 1981, 1986, and undated, 2 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Miller, Jim Wayne, 1979-1986 and undated, 4 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Moore, Lenard D., 1993 (Box WO-7)
  - Moran, Barbara Baillet, 1982 (Box WO-7)
  - Morgan, Robert, 1968-1970, 1991, 3 folders (Box WO-7)
  - Morrison, Dorothy, 1970 (Box WO-7)
  - A Celebration of Mountain Writing, 1991 (Box WO-7)
  - The Store of Joys, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Murphy, Timothy, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Naumoff, Lawrence, 1996 (Box WO-7)
  - Nixon, Sallie, 1990 (Box WO-7)
  - Nolan, Tony, 1986 (Box WO-7)
  - Nordan, Lewis, 1997 (Box WO-7)
  - Norris, Leslie, 1991 (Box WO-7)
  - Novakovich, Josip, 1994, 1996, 2 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Osborne, K., undated (Box WO-8)
  - Page, Carolyn, 1994 (Box WO-8)
  - Palumbo, Carmine D., 1995 (Box WO-8)
  - Parker, Christine Lamb, 1988 (Box WO-8)
  - Parker, Michael, 1996 (Box WO-8)
  - Patrick, William B., 1991-1996, 3 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Patterson, Joseph, 1990 (Box WO-8)
  - Pavlich, Walter, 1991 (Box WO-8)
  - Peake, Richard, 1992 (Box WO-8)
  - Peters, Patricia Claire, 1996 (Box WO-8)
  - Pope, Deborah, 1993-1995, 3 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Porter, Joe Ashby, 1996 (Box WO-8)
  - Poteat, William H., 1988 (Box WO-8)
  - Quillen, Rita Sims, 1982-1995, 4 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Ragan, Sam, 1986 (Box WO-8)
  - Rainey, Mark, 1991 (Box WO-8)
  - Ramsey, Paul, 1962-1981, 4 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Renner, Cooper, 1995 (Box WO-8)
  - Riley, James, 1990 (Box WO-8)
  - Roberts, Sherry, 1993 (Box WO-8)
  - Robertson, Brewster Milton, 1996, 2 folders (Box WO-8)
  - Robertson-Lorant, Laurie, undated (Box WO-8)
  - Roche, George, 1989 (Box WO-8)
  - Rogers, Del Marie, 1990 (Box WO-8)
  - Roth, Paul B., 1996 (Box WO-8)
  - Rotha, Charline Thackston, 1990 (Box WO-9)
  - Ruark, Gibbons, 1966-1993 and undated, 4 folders (Box WO-9)
  - Ruffilli, Paolo, 1974 (Box WO-9)
  - Russell, Peter, 1993-1994, 3 folders (Box WO-9)
  - St. Anthony Messenger, 1995-1996 (Box WO-9)
  - Sawyer, Ann, undated (Box WO-9)
  - Schaible, Robert, 1990 (Box WO-9)
  - Schorb, E.M., 1994 (Box WO-9)
  - Seay, James, 1993 (Box WO-9)
  - Secreast, Donald, 1990 (Box WO-9)
  - Sedaris, Crispi, 1996 (Box WO-9)
  - Sen, Sudeep, 1994 (Box WO-9)
  - Settle, Claire, undated (Box WO-9)
  - Settle, Judith H., 1992 (Box WO-9)
  - Shapard, Robert, 1985 (Box WO-9)
  - Shapiro, Alan, undated (Box WO-9)
  - Shelnutt, Eve, 1974-1990 and undated, 7 folders (Box WO-9)
  - Shrum, Lynne, 1997 (Box WO-9)
  - Simms, William Gilmore, 1996 (Box WO-9)
  - Skellings, Edmund, 1981, 1985, 2 folders (Box WO-9)
  - Slavitt, David R., 1991-1995 and undated, 4 folders (Box WO-9)
  - Smith, Lee, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Smith, R.T., 1981 (Box WO-10)
  - Smith-Soto, Mark, 1993 (Box WO-10)
  - Snodgrass, W.D., 1990. See also Oversize Material (Box WO-10)
  - Snotherly, Mary Carleton, 1994 (Box WO-10)
  - Snow, Phyllis Moore, 1997 (Box WO-10)
  - Socolow, Elizabeth, 1986 (Box WO-10)
  - Soniat, Katherine, 1993, 2 folders (Box WO-10)
  - Speer, Allen, 1992-1993 (Box WO-10)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth, 1997 (Box WO-10)
  - Spera, Gabriel, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - The Spirit that Moves Us Press, 1991 (Box WO-10)
  - Stafford, Frank, 1990 (Box WO-10)
  - Staley, Harry C., 1995 (Box WO-10)
  - Stallings, A.E., 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Steele, Max, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Steinke, Russell, 1980-1981 and undated (Box WO-10)
  - Stephenson, Shelby, 1981-1990 and undated, 4 folders (Box WO-10)
  - Stokesbury, Leon, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Stone, John, 1985 (Box WO-10)
  - Stotler, William, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Stuart, Dabney, 1984-1991, 4 folders (Box WO-10)
  - Stuart, Katherine, 1996 (Box WO-10)
  - Suk, Julie, 1991 (Box WO-10)
  - Sullivan, Chuck, 1983 (Box WO-10)
  - Sullivan, Sally, 1982, 1985, 2 folders (Box WO-10)
  - Sutton, Maureen Douglas, 1995 (Box WO-11)
  - Swann, Brian, undated (Box WO-11)
  - Sykes, D.M., 1985, 2 folders (Box WO-11)
  - Tarkington, Tim, 1976 (Box WO-11)
  - Taylor, Elanor Ross, 1996 (Box WO-11)
  - Taylor, Henry, 1993 (Box WO-11)
  - Taylor, Peter, 1994 (Box WO-11)
  - Taylor, Ron, 1991 (Box WO-11)
  - Texas Review, 1991 (Box WO-11)
  - Umphrey, Michael, 1994 (Box WO-11)
  - Venters, Travis, 1976 (Box WO-11)
  - Victoria Press, 1996 (Box WO-11)
  - Voight, Ellen Bryant, 1994 (Box WO-11)
  - Watson, Robert, 1996 (Box WO-11)
  - Way, Roy, 1995 (Box WO-11)
  - Weatherford, Carole Boston, 1995 (Box WO-11)
  - Weaver, Gordon, 1990 (Box WO-11)
  - Wellspring, 1991 (Box WO-11)
  - West, Cameron John, 1996 (Box WO-11)
  - Whatley, Wallace, 1979 (Box WO-11)
  - Wilkinson, Sylvia, 1993 (Box WO-11)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1982 (Box WO-11)
  - Williams, Miller, undated (Box WO-11)
  - Wood, Tex, 1986 (Box WO-11)
  - Wooten-Hawkins, Anna, 1986 (Box WO-11)
  - Yarbrough, Steve, 1994, 2 folders (Box WO-11)
  - York, John Thomas, undated (Box WO-11)
  - Zalamea, Luis, 1984 (Box WO-11)
  - Zarucchi, Roy, 1990 (Box WO-11)
  - Unknown, 1994 ( Cullen) (Box WO-11)
  - Unknown, 1996 ( Belated a Bit, But Sure) (Box WO-11)
  - Unknown, undated (Box WO-11)
- Oversize Material, 1963-1997 and undated
  Consists of several oversize proofs of Chappell books, a few proofs by other authors, and miscellaneous items such as broadsides, posters, oversize serials, and memorabilia. Arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
  - Writings by Chappell Series, Fiction Subseries
    - Dagon (1968), 2 folders (Box OM-1)
      - proof, 1968 (Box OM-1)
      - proof, undated, with several chapters of The Gaudy Place handwritten on verso (Box OM-1)
    - The Gaudy Place (1973) (see also Dagon in Oversize Materials Series), 2 folders
      - first proof--author's marked set, 1972 Oct. 23 (Box OM-1)
      - first proof, 1972 Nov. 27 (Box OM-1)
    - The Inkling (1965)
      - proof, 1965 Feb. 8-17 (Box OM-1)
    - It Is Time, Lord (1963), 2 folders
      - author's proof, 1963 Mar. 7-16 (Box OM-1)
      - author's proof, 1963 Apr. 19 (Box OM-1)
    - Moments of Light (1980)
      - proof, ca. 1980 (Box OM-1)
  - Writings by Chappell Series, Poetry Subseries
    - Earthsleep (1980)
      - proof, ca. 1980 (Box OM-1)
    - Wind Mountain (1979)
      - proof, 1979 Mar. 12 (Box OM-1)
    - The World Between the Eyes (1971)
      - proof with Chappell's corrections, 1971 (Box OM-1)
  - Writings by Chappell Series, Essays Subseries
    - Family Matters (1991, Georgia Review), galley proof, 1991 Nov. 26 (Box OM-1)